RYAN GUIDO

https://github.com/ryang-123 https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanguido/ ryanguido29@gmail.com * (647) 529-5404 Vaughan, Ontario, Canada, L6A3X3

ABOUT ME https://ryanguido.me/

Proactive, adaptable 3rd-year Computer Science student with strong background in programming languages including Java, JavaScript, Python, HTML5, CSS, PHP, Turing, and SQL. Experience with a variety of frameworks such as Bootstrap, React.js, Node.js, JQuery, and Express. Mobile app development experience in Android Studio. Team Collaboration platform experience in JIRA/Tempo, Slack, and GitHub (Version Control). Comfortable with Windows, Linux, and Mac OS operating systems.

EDUCATION

Honors BSc, Computer Science Lassonde School of Engineering, York University Expected April 2021 Toronto, ON

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Application Developer

York University – Sensorimotor Control Lab

September 2019 – Present

- Maintain/enhance existing visuomotor experiment python code (PyVMEC) as per requests made by the lab leader and technicians
- Help develop integration platform for web-based experiments using JavaScript, PHP, HTML, and CSS
- Assist lab workers in other programming projects within the lab environment

Web/Application Developer (Intern)

K2XO

May - August 2019

- Work in a full-stack environment performing both front and back-end development on various projects
- Conduct projects in an "Agile" project workflow, following proper Software Development Life Cycle practices and procedures via JIRA/Tempo
- Work alongside members of the project team (namely the VP of Technology, Full-Stack Developer Lead, Art Director, and designers) and assist in all aspects of a project
- Participate in all project meetings including demos and sprint planning

Jr. Front-End Developer

York University

October 2018 – April 2019

- Maintain various Faculty of Environmental Studies websites under the guidance and direction of the supervisor
- · Work with content management systems such as Drupal and WordPress to develop various plug-in/theme components
- Create/develop/ edit web graphics, web templates and/or modules as needed
- Assist in the writing of instructions and documentation

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

- Staff Contributor/Writer at Sunday Puncher Boxing, January 2018 Present
- Crew Trainer at McDonald's Canada, January 2014 to Present
- Creative Video Intern at MuggleNet.com, November 2018 February 2019
- New Accounts Officer (Intern) at Scotiabank, Summer 2017 and 2018
- Line Cook at Canada's Wonderland, Summer 2016

INDEPENDENT SOFTWARE PROJECTS — Available for viewing at https://ryanguido.me/ and GitHub

- **ClubHub**: A re-envisioned version of the York U club website. Users can discover clubs using the search bar or by checking the preloaded list of clubs. Club information can also be added to Google Calendar. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Google Scripts, Google Calendar API, Google Sheets
- **DEM Smart:** A smart home utility for people suffering with dementia. The Google Calendar API and the Bose Sound touch Control API allows a user (specifically family member) to set and trigger specific reminders for various situations throughout a day. Google Calendar API, the Bose SoundTouch Control API, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Python, and a Bose SoundTouch 10 speaker
- Lumos App: A simple flashlight app mimicking a wand tip illuminating on screen when the flashlight is turned on. The app utilizes the Android Camera API, specifically its Torch settings. Java, Android Studio